chaumet.com 2016-10-13

# Legal terms & Privacy policy | Chaumet

Welcome to the Internet site (hereinafter referred to as the “Website”) published by Chaumet International (hereinafter referred to as “Chaumet”), a public limited company (société anonyme under French Law) with a share capital of €35,848,725 registered on the Register of Commerce of Paris under no. B 342 966 942, whose registered office is at 12, place Vendôme, 75001 Paris (France).

Contact:  
Tel.: +33 (0)1 44 77 26 26

Publication Manager: Mrs Anne-Line Roccati, Communication Director  
Editorial Content Manager: Mrs Claire Schmitt, Head of Internet Projects.

Hosted by: LinkByNet, Parc du Colombier - 5-9 rue de L’industrie - 93200 Saint-Denis - France  
Tel : + 33 (0)1 48 13 00 00

Use of this Website is subject to the following terms and conditions (hereinafter referred to as the “Conditions”). Chaumet reserves the right to periodically amend these Conditions. The amended Conditions shall become effective as of the date they are posted on the Website. Please read these Conditions carefully before using this Website. Website users acknowledge the fact that they have been made aware, from the moment of connection, of the existence of Terms and Conditions of Website Use. Consequently, continuing use of the Website is construed to mean that the user has fully and completely agreed to these Conditions.

Chaumet has created this Website to provide information to users on a personal basis. Users may print or download a copy of the pages of this Website for personal, private and non-commercial use only. Unless otherwise stated, all graphic and text features on the Website, such as brands and photographs, including the models shown, texts, videos, and animations, are protected throughout the world by copyright law, trademark law and the provisions of international treaties.

These features may not be modified or used in any way whatsoever for public or commercial purposes, and in particular, reproduced, displayed for the public, sold or integrated into a derivative work. Features on this Website must not be used or presented on any other Internet sites or within any networked computer environments for any purpose whatsoever.

3.1 General information  
The following text details the manner in which Chaumet uses and collects your personal data, and informs you of the measures taken to ensure your data is protected whilst using the website, according to the terms of the French Data Protection Act no. 78-17 of 6 January 1978 (the “Loi Informatique et Libertés", hereinafter the "Data Protection Act"), as amended by the provisions of Law no. 2004-801 of 6 August 2004 concerning the protection of individuals in respect of the processing of personal data.

Chaumet protects the privacy of its Website users by complying with the applicable legislation in force. It has therefore notified the French Data Protection Authority (Commission Nationale de l'Informatique et des Libertés, hereafter “CNIL”) of the collection and processing of your personal data.

Chaumet may collect your personal data, in particular through the “Contact” form, when you subscribe to the Chaumet electronic Newsletter, when you create your Chaumet “Account” or when you use our direct telephone service to contact Chaumet Customer Services, as indicated on the form “Speak to an advisor”.

“Personal data” refers to information concerning you as a private individual, which you communicate voluntarily by filling in the form on the Website, or which Chaumet collects during your browsing session; information of any kind that can be used to identify you, directly or indirectly. Personal data includes data such as your name and address, and electronic identification data available on or from your computer (such as “cookies”, “IP addresses” or your browser personal settings). Your electronic identification data identifies your connection terminal or pages viewed on the website during your browsing session and is generally not sufficient on its own to identify you personally.

3.2 Identity of data processing manager and purposes of processing  
The personal data collected on this Website may be used by Chaumet International (hereinafter “Chaumet”), a French limited company (société anonyme) with a capital of €35,848,725, registered in the Paris Trade and Companies Register under number B 342 966 942, with its registered office at 12, place Vendôme, 75001 Paris (France), as data processing manager, for the purposes of:  
\- managing relations with customers and prospective customers via the web “Contact” form and the “Speak to an advisor” form  
\- offering them its services, such as setting up and sharing a selection of gift ideas, subscription to the Chaumet newsletter, creation of a personal "Your Account" space, which saves the gift selections previously made, personal data which the user can modify, the details of their favourite store.

Some of the personal data collected will be used to send you information newsletters and marketing e-mails. We will ensure that you have given us your prior consent on the data collection form on the Website, by ticking the “Yes” box in response to the question “I wish to receive news from Chaumet about new products, events and special offers".

The information required by Chaumet to fulfil the missions described above is marked by an asterisk on the different pages of the Website. The other information is optional and helps us to understand you better, and to improve our communications and services to you. The specific information collected by Chaumet is your full name, postal address, e-mail address, date of birth and telephone number.

3.3 Rights held by users concerning control over their data (right of access, correction and objection)

Users who have supplied their personal data through the Website have the right to access and correct any personal data which is inaccurate (by sending a letter accompanied by a copy of an identity document including a signature) to our Customer Services Department:  
\- by mail: By writing to Chaumet Service Relation Clientèle [Customer Services Department] – 12, place Vendôme 75001 Paris, France  
\- by e-mail: by sending an e-mail to information@chaumet.com.

Users also have the right to object to the processing of their data for legitimate reasons, and a right to object to use of the data for purposes of sales canvassing, by contacting the department indicated above.  
The Website offers users the opportunity to subscribe to a Newsletter which contains information on Chaumet products, new products and events etc.

Users who no longer wish to receive the Newsletter can unsubscribe by:  
\- simply clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each Newsletter.  
\- clicking on the unsubscribe link here.   
\- filling in the “Contact” form specifying your request and the e-mail address you wish to unsubscribe in your message.

So that we can meet your request, you must give us the information necessary to identify you: your last name, first name, e-mail address and your postal address, where appropriate.

3.4 Sharing and disclosure of personal data  
Chaumet and Chaumet’s suppliers are the only recipients of the data collected. Within Chaumet, your personal data may be sent to the marketing departments and the departments responsible for customer services at Chaumet. External suppliers to whom your personal data may be communicated will be our suppliers responsible for hosting and maintaining the website.

Chaumet will only transmit your personal data to a third party if:  
\- you have given us prior consent to share this information (for example for a special promotional event);   
\- Chaumet has to share this information with its suppliers, in particular its technical suppliers, in order to provide you with the service you have requested - for example sending the Newsletter;  
\- Chaumet has received a demand from a legal authority or any administrative authority authorised by the law, requesting the sending of this information in accordance with the legislative provisions in force.

When you want to tell a friend about a Chaumet product using the “Share” functions on the Website, you expressly acknowledge that you have obtained the consent of the e-mail recipient.

3.5 Retention of data  
Chaumet may retain your personal data for a period not exceeding five years from the last date of contact.

3.6 Security measures  
Chaumet will do its best to protect your personal data against damage, loss, misappropriation, intrusion, disclosure, alteration or destruction.

Chaumet’s computer hardware and software is protected by a state of the art system. We implement physical and electronic back-ups of the data collected on the website, in accordance with current French legislation concerning personal data protection.

The Chaumet employees who may have access to your personal data, in the course of their duties, undertake to treat it with the strictest confidentiality.

However, Chaumet cannot control the risks related to the Internet and would like to draw your attention to the existence of potential risks such as occasional loss of data or attack on the confidentiality of data transiting the network. The information displayed on the Website may be interrupted in cases of force majeure or events beyond Chaumet's control, or events for which Chaumet is not responsible.

3.7 Information concerning cookies and browser preferences  
Firstly, a cookie (also known as a “web cookie” or “browser cookie”) is a file saved on your hard disk by an Internet server for a limited temporary period, to facilitate your browsing and improve the quality of our Website. Also it is important to make the difference between “browsing cookies” and “web analytic cookies”.

Browsing cookies enable Chaumet to record information such as your e-mail address, your “Account” login, and the search terms you have entered in our Website search engine, in order to facilitate your browsing session. They only last for the period of your web session, i.e. 20 minutes from your last action on one of the Website pages.

Chaumet also uses certain preferences in your browser such as language or Java Script activation, to facilitate your browsing session. For example, when it detects your browser’s language, Chaumet offers you the most appropriate version of the Website.

Web analytic cookies enable Chaumet to store information concerning your browsing, such as pages you have viewed, the time and date of viewing, the place of your connection etc. We cannot identify you personally from these cookies; the data they collect is aggregated and allocated to a unique impersonal user. These data enable Chaumet to analyse the relevance of the Website content so that it can be improved. These data may be kept for up to 2 years, to enable a comparative analysis over time. To do so, Chaumet uses a third-party solution by Google Analytics. If you wish to opt-out from Google Analytics, please click here.

You can refuse the cookies by changing the settings of your web browser. This operation may however remove all the cookies used by your browser, including those used by other websites, which may result in alteration or loss of certain settings or information. Deleting cookies may change your browsing session or even make it difficult to browse the Chaumet website.

You may object to the saving of cookies on your hard disk by configuring your browser as follows:

For Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0 and higher:  
1\. Select the “Tools” menu, then “Internet Options”.  
2\. Click on the “Confidentiality” tab  
3\. Select the level required using the cursor.

For Microsoft Internet Explorer 5:  
1\. Select the “Tools” menu, then “Internet Options”.  
2\. Click on the “Security” tab  
3\. Select “Internet” then “Custom Level”  
4\. Click on the “cookies” section and select the appropriate option

For Netscape 6.X and 7. X:  
1\. Select the “Edit”>”Preferences” menu  
2\. Confidentiality and Security  
3\. Cookies

For Firefox:  
1\. Select the “Tools”>”Options” menu  
2\. Click on the "Privacy" option

For Safari 3.x for Mac OS X  
1\. Select the “Edit” menu  
2\. Click on the “Preferences” option  
3\. Click on the “Security” option  
4\. Click on “Display cookies".

The information available on the Website is published for general information purposes only. While Chaumet takes great care to provide accurate information, it cannot guarantee the accuracy, precision or comprehensiveness of information published on the Website and cannot be liable in the event of error or inaccuracy. Users use the Website at their own risk. 

Products sold by Chaumet are available in many countries of the world. The Website may however describe certain products that are not sold throughout the world. 

Chaumet cannot be held liable for direct or indirect losses that may arise from the use of the Website, including inaccessibility, data loss, deterioration, destruction or viruses that may affect users’ computer hardware and/or the presence of viruses on the Website.

All features of this Website are protected by French and international copyright and intellectual property law. All intellectual property rights to Website features, in particular trademarks, brands, patents, designs logos and other distinctive marks, are the exclusive property of Chaumet. Consequently, any total or partial reproduction of features from the Website is strictly prohibited, unless previously authorised in writing by Chaumet. Reproduction of certain features of the Website is authorised only for the purpose of personal and private information. Any reproduction or use of copies made for any other purpose is expressly prohibited.

These conditions have been drawn up in accordance with French law, in particular the provisions of Law no. 2004-575 of 21 June 2004 concerning trust in the digital economy, and Law no. 78-17 of 6 January 1978 concerning Data Protection (hereinafter the "Data Protection Act"), as amended by the provisions of Law no. 2004-801 of 6 August 2004 concerning the protection of individuals in respect of the processing of personal data. The French courts of Paris will have jurisdiction over any dispute relating to the website. 

Chaumet does not guarantee that its Website content is adapted for all countries of the world or available for use in all countries. Users must ensure that they comply with applicable regulations in their countries, it being understood that access to Website content may be considered illegal for certain people or in certain countries. 

If Chaumet were to waive the right to enforce proceedings concerning the breach of any of the provisions set forth herein, this may not be construed as a waiver of the right to enforce proceedings concerning the breach of any other provision contained herein.

For any questions or comments related to the Legal Conditions and more specifically to the Personal Data Charter, you can contact our Customer Services Department:  
• by mail: by writing to Chaumet Service Relation Clientèle [Customer Services Department] – 12, place Vendôme 75001 Paris, France  
• by e-mail: information@chaumet.com  
• by telephone: +33 (0)1 44 77 26 26

 _Last update: September 2014, 12th._
